Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
It is the year 0079 of the Universal Century.
Giant space colonies have been built
around the Earth.
As each group of colonies was completed,
it was given a number. Side 1...
...Side 2, and so on.
Two years after
the seventh Side was built...
...war broke out between the Principality
of Zeon and the Earth Federation.
Four Sides were destroyed
during the fighting...
...and only Side 6 remained.
The White Base, with its young crew...
... is now making its way across
Central Asia toward Europe...
...destroying M'Quve's
mining bases as it goes.
The Trap of M'Quve
He came out!
Damn, I missed him!
Mr. Bright's not going to be too happy.
Mr. Bright, Magella Attacks are
spreading out to starboard!
Mr. Bright, your orders...?
Is something the matter?
No... I'm fine...
Have the Gundam... No...
Have the Guntank take care of defense.
Yes, sir!
Here goes!
Resistance from the enemy base
has completely subsided.
Is that right...
Order the Gundam and the Guntank to return.
Take off quickly as soon as
they're safely aboard.
Bright, what course should I set?
Bright?!
Bright!
Mirai, we're still in battle.
Could someone help him up?
Sure.
Thanks, Job.
Mr. Bright...
That Elran doesn't give me
very much useful information.
Your regular report, sir.
What Is It, sir?
What's this I hear about the loss of
Bauxite Mining Bases No. 7 and No. 86?
The defenses we had
should have been adequate!
But the capabilities of the Trojan Horse and Its
mobile suits were beyond what we expected.
That's enough.
I'll take care of the rest.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Judock. Go tell General Elran this...
For the entire day tomorrow...
... he must slow down the movement of
Federation forces in Eastern Europe.
Y-Yes. I understand, sir!
Mr. Judock.
Yes, sir?
Fix your uniform.
Your Federation collar is showing.
Nice and clean.
Hey, you!
Hey! Settle down!
Hey!
See, I warned you!
Now, you have to rinse off completely.
What is it?
You and Kikka are both girls, right?
That's right.
Then why is Kikka so flat here?
Naughty boy!
Hey, Hayato!
Can you get me
replacement part No. 1-33?
All right!
Huh?
Isn't it there?
No.
I'm sure the Medea delivered it the other day.
If we don't replace it, it'll still work...
... but it's a class D consumable part,
so the unit will be much less reliable.
It must have been put away somewhere.
I'll go ask Mr. Bright.
I'll go too. There're other parts
I have to talk to him about.
Hey, Amuro.
Hi.
Hello.
My...
What is it?
You two stink.
It's true! You really stink!
Phew!
- Stinky!
- So stinky!
You two should at least use the shower.
We don't have time for that.
See you...
Oh, you filthy creatures!
Filthy!
Huh? Where's Mr. Bright?
He's in the infirmary. What is it?
Then... where's Ms. Mirai?
She's checking on Mr. Bright
in the infirmary.
We really need her here now.
She should let Sunmalo take care of him.
This is a problem.
The hangar's this way, Amuro.
I'll drop by the infirmary and ask.
I'll wait in the hangar.
Okay.
The fever isn't going down.
I gave him a sedative just now.
It'll come down soon.
Oh, Amuro. is there something you want?
No. Excuse me.
So, did you ask about the parts?
No.
Vice! They'll be passing over us
any moment now.
I want you all
to check your equipment again.
Don't carry even a sliver of metal.
Lang, take off your watch.
It's all plastic,
like the rest of the equipment.
Everyone, put on your lift jets!
How's the gas pressure in the lift jets?
We're all okay.
We checked it before too.
I'm sure it's right.
They're coming.
Those guys are in for a shock.
They can't detect us at all.
Lang, keep your mouth shut
until we've succeeded.
All right.
How is he?
Well, according to the computer,
it's just exhaustion.
He should be all right
after 2 or 3 days of rest.
I see.
How did it go?
Don't know yet.
W-What was that?!
An explosion...!
What's going on?!
They got us!
I don't know how they did it, but
they got our Minovsky particle emitters...
...and the E.C.M. transmitters!
That means...
Yes. We're completely vulnerable
to the enemy's sensors.
What about the radar?
It's undamaged.
I wonder why they didn't destroy it, too.
I don't know.
Ms. Mirai, please don't think that
the operators overlooked something.
I would never...!
Operators, sound the alarm anyway.
Put everyone on level 2 battle stations.
Yes.
Damn! No more time
for replacing parts!
Incoming!
Formation of 20 Dopp-like aircraft!
Must be fighters! Amuro! Ryu...!
No! Amuro! Hayato!
Launch Core Fighters, please!
Mobile Suit
Gundam
Please hurry with the Core Fighter launch!
Hayato! I'll go ahead!
But we should stay close together
when we fight. Got it?!
Roger!
Another Dopp formation!
You've got to be kidding, Amuro!
Two Core Fighters are no match against that!
I agree! What was she thinking
when she deployed the Core Fighters?!
Another formation incoming!
Course, 2-70! Speed, Mach 5!
Altitude, 12,000! About 15 fighters!
Sayla!
Should we deploy the Guntank
to the rear for cover?
There's no way we can do that.
First wave, at 12 o'clock, directly overhead!
Amuro! Hayato!
Cover the White Base!
Roger!
It's no good! There're too many of them!
You mustn't, Mr. Bright!
To the bridge...
You're kidding! Not in your condition!
Why can't I move my body?
Am I afraid?
Ryu...!
Huh?
Ryu! Cover the port side
with the Guncannon!
Mr. Bright...
We'll launch the Gundam
and Guntank parts.
Please inform the mechanics.
Mirai! You're making them
do a mid-air transfer...
...without the Gunperry,
and during battle?!
ls that wrong?
If deploying the Core Fighters
was a mistake...
... I have to correct it right away!
Mirai, I think Amuro is capable of doing it.
But Hayato...
Then we can have Hayato transfer
on the White Base.
It's perfect, Sayla.
We'll do both at once!
All right.
What?! A mid-air transfer during battle?!
How am I supposed to do that?!
Sorry about that.
We're launching the Gundam parts.
Hayato, return to the White Base
and transfer to the Guncannon.
Why don't you use Mr. Kai?
He's right there!
Sorry... Kai's on the anti-air turrets
and can't leave.
I understand.
Please launch the Gundam parts.
Don't blame me if the Gundam gets hit!
They're going too fast!
I wish they'd consider my situation!
Sensor synchronized!
Launching A Parts!
They're rushing too much!
Gundam! Here I go!
Our plan to flush out the Trojan Horse...
... is proceeding quite well.
Be careful, Hayato!
They've spread a net on the ground as well.
Got it?!
Y-Yeah...
No one told us the Zeons had
such a powerful force in this area.
We just have to accept reality.
Y-You're right...
Marker! Can you find us an escape route?
70 degrees to starboard
is relatively clear.
Roger that.
And they don't even know why
we let them keep their radar.
Because they have the radar...
...they analyze the situation
and fall into our trap on their own.
Impressive as always, Captain.
I suppose.
Hayato!
I'm out of ammo! I'll just have to...
Now!
Hayato! Does the Guncannon
have any ammo left?!
That was the last!
All right! Cover me!
You!
Can't take much more of this.
Where's the White Base?
Hayato! Let's jump and get out of here!
All right?!
Okay!
Two enemy mobile suits
have escaped from our encirclement!
Oh well. We'll just finish them
along with the Trojan Horse.
We've been hit in Blocks 13 and 16!
Are the engines all right?
We can still fly!
Then we're going to run!
Is running all you think about?!
This is the best I can do!
What more do you want from me?!
I wish Ryu were here at a time like this...
No...!
Gundam and Guncannon, back on board!
Can they do another sortie, Sayla?
I'll ask. I doubt it's possible, though.
Ms. Sayla! How long do you think it takes
to replenish our weapons and energy?!
Please think reasonably
about the situation!
Amuro, that's going too far.
We're giving orders
based on the overall situation.
I'm going out as soon as
the beam rifle's ready.
All right! It'll be about 2 minutes!
If only Ryu were here now...
Hayato! Don't say that!
That's right...Good...
Come in a little bit further.
Strange. The Dopps are withdrawing.
Already?!
We have to get out of here now!
Go after the Dopps! Hurry!
Let us shut down main engine No. 2!
It'll explode at this rate!
Pressure build-up in the third nozzle
of main engine No. 1.
We have to shut it down, quickly!
So it was that mega particle cannon!
I'll take it out... in one shot!
It's all over!
What are you saying, Mirai?
You're in command now!
I can't!
We're done for...
Ms. Mirai...
What?! The attack force is returning!
They're going to finish us off.
I have an idea!
I don't know if this will work, but...
Huh?
Ms. Sayla...
We take the safety off the smoke bombs...
...and set them off in the launch tubes!
There'll be a lot of damage.
But if we can fool the enemy, we'll survive.
Mirai?
I'll leave it to you. I...
Bright...
Ryu...! Help me...
Bright...! Ryu...!
Help me...!
Oh! They're off the radar!
We're safe for now...
What are we going to do?
Well, the only thing we can do
is ask General Revil for support.
And if it shows up...
What's the battle status?
Ms. Mirai?!
We made it through somehow.
But will we arrive in time for Odessa Day?
Odessa Day...
That's the counter-offensive
in Europe, right?
Sayla...
Sayla!
Please send a coded message
to General Revil of the Federation Forces.
A Medea transport team is
assaulted by Goufs...
...scattering relief supplies in the air.
Even the Gundam, joining in the fight,
is damaged by the Gouf's powerful attack.
After delivering the G Parts from
the transport plane, Matilda cries...
"Rise up, Amuro!"
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
Matilda's Rescue.
Next Time
Matilda's Rescue
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...